♪From primal chaos to the starry sky♪
♪In the whole world,
we shall hold the balance♪
♪The cauldron tempers divine blades♪
♪The furnace refines the empty void♪
♪The Way is in mystic fate♪
♪Be brave enough to split
the primal chaos wide open♪
[Pull Strings]
[Adapted from the novel
by Yan Gui Zheng Zhuan]
[Episode 6]
This is
the Ascendance Sect?
What are
all these things?
Your Highness,
they're humans.
So,
this is
human.
Welcome, Prince Ao Jia
of the East Sea.
Dragon Palace Envoy brings a message.
Master of Ascendance Sect.
Come at once to meet.
Who dares be so insolent?
So, you're
the Grandlord of Ascendance Sect?
Have you no manners?
The prestigious Ascendance Sect
isn't for a beast like you to question.
How dare you!
This is the Crown Prince of East Sea.
What are you to disrespect him?
I don't care.
Since you've come to my sect,
you must obey my rules.
Then let me
teach you a lesson.
Come.
If you can even scratch
one dragon scale,
I'll immediately kneel and swear fealty.
How about that?
Good.
Your Highness.
So, this is the Human Clan.
No need for you to step in.
Impossible!
I am a Celestial Immortal.
How could a beast defeat me?
Impossible!
You had enough fun?
Now,
it's my turn.
[Detached Master,
Grandlord of Ascendance Sect]
Breaths restored. Heavens as one.
Break!
Go.
Your Highness.
Your Highness, are you alright?
The Human Clan is so despicable.
Let's not stoop to their level.
Are you alright?
Let me see.
I'm Detached Master,
Grandlord of Ascendance Sect.
Greetings, Crown Prince.
The proud dragon shall know regret.
Strength to the extreme brings disgrace.
I urge you to reconsider.
Mentor.
Mentor, you've emerged from seclusion.
Your Highness,
His Majesty has ordered:
No trifles, no big trouble.
Yes, Your Highness.
We are
outnumbered.
Turn around.
Before so many people?
I don't need you to teach me how to act.
The proud dragon shall know regret, huh?
When you sought
to exterminate us,
did you ever regret it?
For nearly a thousand years,
you've dwelt in the four seas,
with strife unceasing.
Under the pretext of the tides,
you stirred up trouble.
For the bond between our clans,
we only gave a light punishment
as a warning.
We never tried to exterminate you.
A light punishment as a warning?
If you don't exterminate us now,
you'll exterminate us eventually.
You humans always lie.
I won't fall for your tricks.
You've come with such a crowd,
just to engage in a war of words?
A timely reminder.
Now, let us speak of business.
Some days ago,
you held a Training Assembly.
Many of our soldiers were hurt.
By all rights,
all who struck them should be seized
and punished without mercy.
Unfortunately,
my always speaks
of harmony between our peoples.
He told me not to stoop to your level.
They invite us to the East Sea
to settle this matter in three days.
The courteous words
have now been delivered.
In three days,
we shall meet at Dragon Palace.
Mentor,
we have no ties with Dragon Palace.
I fear this feast bodes ill.
We must go. Courtesy demands it.
Besides,
if the peace between humans and dragons
falls apart because of us,
then in the future,
how can I face our ancestors?
The crisis has passed.
We'll decide the attendees later.
All divisions, you're dismissed.
Understood.
The invitation of the Dragon Palace
of the East Sea.
What a great chance!
I must guard the Sea-Calming Pillar
for the Celestial Court.
Greetings, Grandlord.
Come.
Quickly, rise.
Yuan.
You've been through a lot.
Look.
Wear it properly.
Yuan?
Who doesn't have a pet name?
Grandlord.
It's fine, it's fine.
Even when Mentor has nothing to do,
he still coughs up bottles
of blood daily.
If I could spit up so much,
that would be a true blessing.
To expel the old and take in the new
is the true essence of the Way.
To expel the old and take in the new...
Yuan.
- How enviable.
- Grandlord, here.
This...
Coughing blood isn't expelling the old.
His body seems...
A minor injury.
These things happen.
My mentor taught me long ago.
I've gotten used
to spitting up blood.
That's right.
- What teaching is this?
- I'm used to it.
Yuan,
if trouble ever finds you,
come to me for help.
Look, tighten your clothes.
You're all disheveled.
It's not proper before the juniors.
I won't look. I won't look.
Fix your clothes.
What to do?
Sixty years ago,
you borrowed my Gnatsting Needle
to remove a nagging worry.
From then on, you were enlightened,
advancing by leaps and bounds.
Now, a mere lackey of the Dragon Palace
can hold his own against you.
The Grandlord you most wish to topple
has become much more powerful.
Silence!
Only by growing stronger
can one be truly invincible.
We can give you
what your sect can't.
Be quiet! Enough!
There, there.
My dear elder,
why not leave this sea of suffering
and reach the other shore?
You should
simply convert to our side.
Look!
If the last Tribulation Cloud
was a false alarm,
then this time,
this Tribulation Cloud seems odd.
A Celestial Immortal becoming
an Aureate Immortal
is a grand spectacle.
You don't see this every year.
Who would have thought
Kuai Si would pass first?
[Hall of Virtue]
If Mentor makes it,
he could rival the Grandlord.
More than that.
By then, our division
will rise in standing with him.
This...
Congrats on becoming
an Aureate Immortal.
Elder Kuai Si quelled evil spirits.
His merit is complete.
Let the 800 divisions celebrate.
What now?
This is...
Had I not lost to the Dragon Clan,
I couldn't have reached this.
I wish to attend the Grand Feast
at the Dragon Palace as well
to cleanse my past shame.
Grandlord, please
grant your consent.
One alone can lead the banquet party.
Okay.
I'll have Wu stay.
You will go in his place.
Yes, Grandlord.
I've helped you become
an Aureate Immortal,
and you've become my fellow disciple.
Time to offer a pledge of allegiance.
You must go to the East Sea on a task.
You'll be briefed on the specifics.
You
should just wait.
Who?
Uncle,
let me help you.
Why are you on the ship?
You're not on the roster.
Like you, Uncle,
I was added at the last minute.
I was too scared to come.
But seeing the Dragon Prince so furious,
after much thought,
I still came, thick-skinned.
Really?
I can't hide it from you, Uncle.
I truly have selfish motives.
I want to see the Dragon Palace
and broaden my view,
so I could brag to the guys later.
But rest assured, Uncle.
About your reckoning
with the Dragon Clan,
I'll stand by your side
and cheer you on.
You are truly an honest man.
But my affairs
are none of your concern.
You insist on wading into this mire.
Just don't regret it later.
Let me help you, Uncle.
Uncle.
Changshou.
I'm here.
Let go.
Stay out of it.
Yes.
Uncle, watch your step.
[Asura Cave]
I've done
what needed to be done.
Kuai Si now obeys me completely.
That should be enough for my report.
You've toiled for sixty years.
Cultivator, what a great service.
What cultivator?
Call me Queen.
Queen, you've done a great service.
I sincerely admire you.
Jin Chan,
don't be so sarcastic with me.
It's not that I'm stalling on purpose.
The Way sects' roots run deep
in Central Plains.
Dragging them into this won't be easy.
My blood's almost run dry
from exhaustion.
And you...
You old stink bug.
You've been idling
in the East Sea for so long.
You haven't forgotten
the real matter, right?
Don't worry.
The hunter has cast the net.
Next,
just listen quietly
to the moment blood is drawn.
[Jin Chan, Guest Official of East Sea]
The pain is gone.
No matter what stubborn illness,
it's no match for your blade, sir.
Your Highness,
it's just pent-up emotions.
Even without seeking my help,
a few days' rest will drive it away.
I wish I could.
I don't have the time.
Speaking of which,
those human scum are about to arrive.
Father leaves me
to host them all.
Then I'll give them a warm welcome.
After all,
of all your teachings, sir,
I best remember one thing:
Humans
and dragons
are sworn enemies.
No matter how many past grievances,
the humans are honored guests.
You must not breach etiquette.
Sir, you are truly merciful.
But didn't you teach me the principle
of courtesy before force?
If there's no excuse,
I will give them one.
You are frail, sir.
No need to see me off.
My heart pounds like a drum.
Truly,
most pleasing to the ear.
It looks like extra rations tonight.
Mind your manners!
Are you the esteemed envoys
of Ascendance Sect?
Yes.
And who might this seafood be?
Who might you be?
I am Jinli, the Dragon Palace General,
sent by the First Prince to welcome you.
Where is the Dragon Palace entrance?
The Dragon Palace has always had
only one entrance.
Are you afraid of water?
Afraid of water?
Forget it. Too late now.
Open the Dragon Gate.
Fear-mongering.
Hold on tight.
I...
Changshou,
I thought you couldn't touch women.
Good heavens! Hold steady!
Hold on to me, Xuanya.
The Dragon Palace trip is so perilous.
Senior Changshou, Junior Ling'e,
why must you come?
Exactly.
Changshou, are you okay?
Senior.
Are you okay, Changshou?
This is the Dragon Palace!
How many treasures must be inside!
If you grab a handful,
you'll be set for half a lifetime.
We're here to broaden our horizons.
That's right.
[Token]
Senior.
[Plaza outside the Crystal Palace,
Token]
Are you all right?
Everyone, what happened?
Are you seasick?
We're here with goodwill
for the feast.
Why make things difficult, Crown Prince?
Elder, please don't take offense.
I'm the Turtle Minister of the East Sea.
It's quite obvious, isn't it?
The Water Dragon Spout is known
as the Dragon Gate.
Only our Dragon Gate Token
and the Dragon King's direct descendants
can open it.
I have sent
your little boat to the surface.
It'll stay there.
When you ride
the Water Dragon Spout out,
you'll see it.
That's right.
Everyone,
leaping this Dragon Gate
is a tremendous honor.
Without leaping it to enter
or leave the East Sea,
you'd have to dive
through unfathomable depths.
So, I hope you all
can relax and open your hearts.
After all,
the ground beneath your feet today
is the Dragon Palace.
Enough, Turtle Minister.
Don't make everyone stand while talking.
I prepared today's banquet
especially for the Ascendance Sect.
Come.
Please take the seats.
Kids don't drink.
The Dragon King
called us to the East Sea
to clear up the misunderstanding.
But where is the Dragon King?
Father
is indisposed.
He bade me act in his stead
and receive you all.
The East Sea abounds in treasures
and rare delicacies.
Everyone,
please enjoy yourselves.
I'll take them back.
Senior,
you won't eat any of these, right?
If not, it'd be a waste.
I'll take them back for Mentor.
Seven.
Eight.
- Nine.
- What are you counting?
Junior,
when we entered the Dragon Palace,
how many of us were there?
Our group had eight.
And you and I sneaked in.
That makes ten.
Ten from Ascendance Sect,
one Dragon Clan General.
So, the total should be...
Eleven.
No,
there are twelve.
Senior,
who taught you to count?
It should be eleven people,
but there are twelve spiritual senses.
Don't look around; it's conspicuous.
What does that mean?
It means
someone secretly tailed us
into the Dragon Palace.
Who?
Where is he?
I'm going to pass out now.
Pass out?
Senior.
I'll pass out too then.
How is it?
Our poison
is no worse than yours
in the human world, right?
You poisoned us?
Why did you poison us?
Why so harsh?
This isn't poisoning.
It's a test for all of you.
A test?
Pah!
This poison
isn't exactly lethal.
It won't be fatal.
At most, just a deep sleep.
Those with high cultivation
will neutralize it with their own power.
Lower cultivation means faster sleep.
This elder
seems to have decent cultivation.
Did you eat differently?
The same.
My wine and food also have poison.
Then, why are you...
I am a dragon.
I was born with a sacred body.
Different from you humans.
I'm not afraid of this poison.
So you see,
compared to dragons, human bodies
are truly weaker.
Turtle Minister,
quickly present the antidote.
Yes.
Zhenzhen, Ai'ai.
Lianlian, Qiezi.
Apply the medicine.
It hurts.
And you are?
She is Jiang Si'er, Princess
[Jiang Si'er, Mermaid Clan]
of the Mermaid Clan.
The First Prince's bride-to-be.
Honored guests,
please don't misunderstand.
The Dragon Palace must stay guarded.
All newcomers must face this trial.
- I'll go.
- We meant no harm.
The antidote was ready all along.
Please forgive us.
You released it too soon.
I was just getting started.
At this point,
the banquet may now come to an end.
Honored guests,
please follow the palace guards
to your chambers and rest.
Once the Dragon King recovers,
he will receive you all.
Wait.
[Ao Yi, Second Prince of East Sea]
Your Highness,
you've returned.
Ao Yi, hurry.
Your Highness?
That's the First Prince;
that's the Second Prince.
Everyone,
allow me to introduce him.
This young man
is Ao Yi, Second Prince
of the Dragon Palace
and my brother.
Good.
If his brother is this arrogant,
what might the younger one be like?
He likely comes with ill intent.
Jia, about this rare banquet today,
I have a request.
Between us, no need for requests.
What is it?
I grew up in the Dragon Palace.
But
I've always heard that the Human Clan
has powerful magic and many heroes,
Jia.
Isn't this mocking us?
Even you caught the mockery.
Even?
So, Yi, what do you mean?
I want to take this chance to test
how strong human Qi refiners really are.
That's my brother.
The true intention is revealed.
Everyone,
the Second Prince wishes to spar.
Surely, no one will object.
Senior,
you're so tall
that you might catch attention.
No, no, Your Highness.
That won't do.
Turtle Minister,
it's a just match for amusement.
His Majesty won't agree.
Father gave me full authority.
If I say a match, then a match it is.
I'll follow your lead.
This height is about right, isn't it?
We're about the same now.
Cover me, help cover me.
Come, Yi.
Pick someone.
Him.
It really is you.
Me?
No, he's too weak.
You'll fight me.
Xuanya will fight
in Senior Changshou's place.
I'll go too.
She can.
Me, me!
- Choose me!
- I can too!
Me! I'll go too!
What a racket!
It's up
to Yi.
No substitutions.
You're the one.
Come here.
So, I can't get away with it.
I'm Li Changshou
of Ascendance Sect.
Greetings, Your Highness.
Li Changshou?
My destined opponent.
Destined?
Have you picked the wrong man?
You are exactly who I seek.
You'll be the first stepping stone
for my grand cause.
It's a trap. I can't get drawn in.
When he strikes,
I'll fake getting hit and fly back.
Catch me.
Rest easy.
But what if you
land right on top of me?
I'm using the One-Way
Voice Transmission.
I can't hear a word you're saying.
Then why did you reply to me?
Don't shame our sect.
Strike him!
On my signal.
Now!
Such formidable skill!
Well done, Changshou!
Pummel him!
Kick him!
Changshou is so weak.
How did he suddenly become strong?
Senior,
why did you fight back?
I didn't.
I thought you couldn't hear me.
I didn't touch him.
Why is he acting
as if I defeated him?
Could it be...
He repelled the Dragon Clan's
Second Prince?
Could he be hiding his cultivation?
Could he have really killed Yuan Qing?
It's a trap.
Has he seen
through my hidden cultivation?
And he wants to expose
my true cultivation?
I won't let you succeed.
Such a strong hidden force.
He really is still quite weak.
I didn't touch him at all.
The Dragon Clan power
is truly formidable.
Without touching me, it wounded me so.
The Second Prince
clearly took my attack
yet is lively and unharmed.
I'm impressed.
Good.
Care to test my resolve too?
So, this is the legendary spell
of releasing power from the eyes?
Amazing!
Our sect has no such move.
My arm...
is broken.
See? It's broken.
You're going this far with me?
Don't doubt my resolve.
Fine.
You forced my hand.
♪Close eyes to sense the world♪
♪Years splash ink♪
♪Trekking far and wide♪
♪Silent in subtleties♪
♪The task descends on me♪
♪Though millions block, it echoes loud♪
♪Transcending gods and demons above♪
♪Plain and unremarkable♪
♪From the start, plan for storms♪
♪Seek refuge, survive, hide my skill♪
Save me, Uncle.
♪Unyielding, who fates good and evil♪
I can't bear to watch.
Uncle,
save me.
Changshou!
First Prince,
the outcome is clear. Stop this.
Please, show mercy.
Yes, yes.
Since the human is coughing blood,
I declare...
The fight isn't over yet.
No, I'll declare the Dragon Clan wins!
I never imagined that I
would meet an opponent like you today.
As expected,
accomplishing great things
always requires the toughest trials.
Stop it!
I'll lose my life if you keep fighting!
Compared to the Dragon Clan's future,
my life
is insignificant.
Could this be
the Human Clan's legendary Sword Flight?
I
hope my death
can awaken the Dragon Clan.
Bro,
you're trying to kill me!
Let's see you keep this act up.
Your Highness!
Take him!
- Senior! - Changshou!
- Yi!
Changshou, Changshou.
Come on, help him up.
Sure.
Hurry, hurry!
Why did it just happen again?
Your Highness.
Yi.
Li Changshou, how are you?
I gave it everything I had
but still couldn't defeat
the Second Prince.
I've brought shame to our sect.
But he's already unconscious.
You,
just put on a good show.
The Second Prince won so easily.
He was overjoyed, which caused a stitch.
Is that so?
Yes, yes, that's right.
Exactly so.
I declare
the Second Prince wins.
Junior.
Senior.
You...
Junior,
help me give the Second Prince
a thumbs-up.
What does this mean?
To pay my highest respects
to the greatest rival
of my acting career.
Senior.
I couldn't make out a word.
♪See mortal joys and sorrows♪
♪Reunions and partings, as fate unfolds♪
♪Alas, love has many twists and turns♪
♪Memories filled with sorrow♪
♪Slowly, wishes turn to regret♪
♪You've gone afar, like mist fading♪
♪Tearfully,
this life's bond is not over♪
♪Past fragments vanish into night♪
♪Down a few more cups of wine♪
♪Through land and sea,
I ask you to come♪
♪For honor's sake, upright and grand♪
♪Alas, our story is short♪
♪Slowly, wishes turn to regret♪
♪You've gone afar, like mist fading♪
♪Tears fall, this fate's not done♪
♪Past fragments vanish into night♪